把手给我！
Give me your hand!
把手给我
Give me your hand.
我以为你说不再疼痛了
I thought you said no more aches or pains.
不，是这可恶的束衣，好紧
No, it's this darned corset. It binds.
没有舒适功能？真是乏味
No three-way stretch? How very un-chic.
你也知道那些警部医生 完全没品味
You know those police department doctors. No sense of style.
反正，就是明天了
Well, anyway, tomorrow will be the day.
明天有什么？
Why, what's tomorrow?
明天？可以脱掉束衣
Tomorrow? The corset comes off tomorrow.
我就可以随我喜欢 任意抓痒
I'll be able to scratch myself like anybody else tomorrow.
我要把这东西扔出窗外
I'll throw this miserable thing out the window.
自由…我就自由了
Be a free... I'll be a free man.
蜜吉，穿束衣的男性多吗？
Midge, do you suppose many men wear corsets?
- 比你认为的还多 - 真的？
- Mmm. More than you think. - Really?
你难道不知道从个人经验或…
What, do you know that from personal experience or...
拜托
Please.
明天之后如何？
What happens after tomorrow?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你退出警察工作后 打算做什么呢？
Well, what are you going to do once you've quit the police force?
听来你不赞成，密吉
You sound so disapproving, Midge.
不会，这是你的人生
No, it's your life.
但你原本是个年轻又有为的律师
But you were the bright, young lawyer that decided
深信自己总会当上警察局长
he was going to be chief of police someday.
我不得不辞
I had to quit.
为什么？
Why?
因为我会怕高，我有惧高症
Well, it's because of this fear of heights I have, this acrophobia.
我会晚上惊醒 看到那个人落下屋顶
I wake up at night seeing that man fall from the roof,
我试着伸手抓他 却…就是…
and I try to reach out to him, and... It's just...
不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
我知道，每个人都这么说
I know. That's what everybody tells me.
强尼，医生解释过…
Johnny, the doctors explained to you...
我懂，我懂
I know, I know.
我有惧高症 会让我晕眩，所以我会头晕
I have acrophobia, which gives me vertigo, and I get dizzy.
唉！知道患上此症时的感觉啊
Boy! What a moment to find out I had it.
你患上了，就摆脱不掉
Well, you've got it, and there's no losing it.
没有人会责怪你，为何辞职？
And there's no one to blame. So why quit?
你要我就坐在书桌前 整日黏在椅子上？
You mean, and sit behind a desk, chair-borne?
你该待的地方
Where you belong.
我的惧高症怎么办？还有…
What about my acrophobia? What about...
假装我坐在椅子上 在书桌前，书桌在这
Now suppose I'm sitting in this chair, behind the desk. Here's the desk.
铅笔从书桌掉到地板上
And a pencil falls from the desk down to the floor,
我弯下腰去捡铅笔 噢！惧高症来了
and I reach down to pick up the pencil. Bingo! My acrophobia's back.
强尼啊
Oh, Johnny-O.
那你要做什么？
Well, what'll you do?
我这阵子什么都做看看
Well, I'm not gonna do anything for a while.
要知道，别忘了 我的财富够我生活无虞
You know, don't forget, I'm a man of independent means, as the saying goes.
可生活无虞
Fairly independent.
你何不远离一阵子？
Well, why don't you go away for a while?
要我忘记吗？
You mean, to forget?
不，蜜吉，别这么慈爱
Oh, no, Midge, don't be so motherly.
我可不会崩溃
I'm not gonna crack up.
你这礼拜发作过头晕现象吗？
Have you had any dizzy spells this week?
我现在就有
I'm having one right now.
蜜吉，这音乐 你不觉得太过…
Midge, the music. Don't you think it's sort of...
这玩意是什么？
What's this doohickey?
胸罩，你已经是大人了 知道这种东西
It's a brassiere. You know about those things. You're a big boy now.
我从没看过这种的
I've never run across one like that.
这是全新的
It's brand-new.
革命式撑托功能 没有肩带、没有背带
Revolutionary uplift. No shoulder straps, no back straps,
但具备胸罩的所有功能
but does everything a brassiere should do.
依悬臂桥的原理作用
Works on the principle of the cantilever bridge.
真的？
- It does? - Mmm-hmm.
旧金山南方的航空工程师设计的
An aircraft engineer down the peninsula designed it.
他用闲暇时间想出来的
He worked it out in his spare time.
像个嗜好
Kind of a hobby.
就像自己想 自己做的设计
A do-it-yourself type of thing.
你的感情生活如何，蜜吉？
How's your love life, Midge?
思想上持续跟进
That's following a train of thought.
一般
Normal.
你没考虑过结婚吗？
Aren't you ever gonna get married?
你知道这世上 只有一个人适合我，强尼
You know there's only one man in the world for me, Johnny-O.
你指的是我 而我们订婚过，不是吗？
You mean me. We were engaged once, though, weren't we?
整整三周
Three whole weeks.
怀念的老大学时代
Good old college days.
但取消订婚的人是你 你还记得吧？
But you were the one that called off the engagement, you remember?
我还是单身 单身的佛格森
I'm still available. Available Ferguson.
蜜吉，还记得大学里 有个叫盖文艾斯特的人吗？
Oh, Midge, do you remember a fellow in college by the name of Gavin Elster?
盖文艾斯特？
Gavin Elster?
对，怪名字
Yes, funny name.
你当我记得，没有
You think I would. No.
我今天接到盖文的电话，真妙
I got a call from Gavin today.
他在大战期间就消失踪影了
It's funny, he sort of dropped out of sight during the war.
有人说他到东岸去 看来他回来了
Somebody said he went East. I guess he's back.
是米慎的号码
It's a Mission number.
那是游民区吧？
Well, that's skid row, isn't it?
或许是
Could be.
他可能正在游荡 跟你接洽只是想讨杯酒喝
He's probably on the bum, and wants to touch you for the price of a drink.
我也正在游荡 我就替他出酒钱，告诉他我的烦恼
Well, I'm on the bum. I'll buy him a couple drinks and tell him my troubles.
但不是今晚 要不要跟我出去喝啤酒？
But not tonight. How about you and me going out for a beer?
抱歉，老头，有工作
Mmm-mmm. Sorry, old man. Work.
好吧，那我就回家
Well, then, I think I'll go home.
蜜吉，你说“摆脱不掉” 是什么意思？
Midge, what'd you mean, "There's no losing it"?
什么？
What?
惧高症
The acrophobia.
我问过医生
I asked my doctor.
他说还需要一次情绪性惊吓 或许有用，或许没用
He said that only another emotional shock could do it and probably wouldn't.
你要不要跳另一个屋顶试试看？
You're not gonna go diving off another rooftop to find out?
- 我应该能克服 - 怎么做？
- I think I can lick it. - Well, how?
我有个理论
I have a theory.
我有个理论，如果我能够 习惯高度的话，每次一点点
I have a theory. I think if I can get used to heights,  just a little bit at a time,
就像，那样 循序渐进，懂了吗？
just a little, like that, progressively, you see?
我做给你看
I'll show you what I mean.
来，我做给你看
Here. I'll show you what I mean.
- 先从这开始 - 那个？
- We'll start with this. - That?
不然从什么开始？ 金门大桥？现在看着
What do you want me to start with, the Golden Gate Bridge? Now, watch.
看好，开始了
Watch this. Here we go.
好了，好了
There. There.
现在，我往上看，我往下看
Now, I look up, I look down.
往上看
I look up.
- 好，这没什么 - 你在搞笑
- All right, there's nothing to it. - You're kidding.
- 等一下 - 这没什么
- Wait a minute. - There's nothing to it.
来
Here.
好家伙，我就用它，放在那儿
That's a girl. I'll use that. Put it right there.
好，开始第一步
All right, here's the first step.
好了
There.
好，再来第二步
Okay, now step number two.
好，开始第二步了
All right. Step number two coming up.
到了
There we are.
瞧？我往上看 往下看，往上看…
See? I look up, I look down, I look up...
我现在就出去 买个不错的高折梯
I'm going right out and buy myself a nice tall stepladder.
先慢慢来
Take it easy now.
好吧，我们继续
All right, now here we go.
没问题
No problem.
瞧，这真简单 来，我往上看，往下看
Why, this is a cinch. Here, I look up, I look down.
往上看，往下看
I look up, I look down.
强尼，强尼
Oh, Johnny, Johnny.
你怎么投入造船事业的，盖文？
How did you get in the shipbuilding business, Gavin?
我一头栽进去
I married into it.
有趣的产业
Very interesting business.
不，说真的，我觉得无聊
No, to be honest, I find it dull.
你不一定要靠这吃饭
Well, you don't have to do it for a living.
不用，但人总该承担责任
No, but one assumes responsibilities.
我太太的家人都走了
My wife's family is all gone.
总有人要照顾她的家族事业
Someone has to look after her interests.
她父亲的伙伴经营东方 巴尔的摩的船厂
Her father's partner runs the company yard in the East, Baltimore.
所以我想既然要投入 我就回这儿做
So I decided, as long as I had to work at it, I'd come back here.
我喜欢这里
I've always liked it here.
你回来多久了？
How long have you been back?
快一年
Almost a year.
喜欢吗？
You like it, huh?
旧金山变了
Well, San Francisco's changed.
让我喜爱旧金山的东西 正迅速消失
The things that spell San Francisco to me are disappearing fast.
就像这些
Like all these.
是，我以前也会喜欢住这儿 色彩、刺激、权力
Yes. I should have liked to have lived here then. Color, excitement, power.
自由
Freedom.
你不坐下吗？
Shouldn't you be sitting down?
不用，不用，我很好
No. No, I'm all right.
我从报纸读到那件事 我很遗憾，而且你辞掉警察工作
I was sorry to read about that thing in the paper. And you've quit the force.
这是永久的实体障碍吗？
Is it a permanent physical disability?
不，不是
No, no.
只是我无法爬那种太陡 或是到高处的楼梯
It just means that I can't climb stairs that are too steep or go to high places,
像是马克酒店顶楼的酒吧
like the bar at the Top of the Mark.
但是这城里 还有不少平面高度的酒吧
But, there are plenty of street-level bars in this town.
你要喝一杯吗？
Would you like a drink now?
不，不用了 不，现在对我来说还太早
No, I don't think so. No, it's a little early in the day for me.
那么，这大概就是 所有的近况，是吧？
Well, I guess that just about covers everything, doesn't it?
我没结婚 我不常见过去的大学朋友们
I never married. I don't see much of the old college gang,
我是个退休的警探 而你在造船业
I'm a retired detective, and you're in the shipbuilding business.
你在想什么，盖文？
What's on your mind, Gavin?
我请你过来，史考特 也知道你辞掉警探工作
I asked you to come up here, Scottie, knowing that you'd quit detective work.
但我想知道你愿不愿意重拾工作 帮我一个忙
But I wondered whether you'd go back on the job as a special favor to me.
请你跟踪我太太
I want you to follow my wife.
不是那样的，我们婚姻很美满
No, it's not that. We're very happily married.
那么…
Well, then...
我担心她会遭遇到危险
I'm afraid some harm may come to her.
来自谁？
From whom?
已死的人
Someone dead.
史考特，你相信过去的人
Scottie, do you believe that someone out of the past,
已死的人 能附身并夺取活人的身体吗？
someone dead, can enter  and take possession of a living being?
不
No.
如果我说这发生在 我太太身上，你怎么说？
If I told you that I believe this has happened to my wife, what would you say?
我会说带她去最近的 精神病医师，或心理医师
Well, I'd say take her to the nearest psychiatrist, or psychologist,
或神经科医师，或神经病 又或许就一般的家庭医师
or neurologist, or psycho... Or maybe just the plain family doctor.
我也会叫他检查你
I'd have him check on you, too.
那我找你就没用了 很抱歉浪费你的时间
Then you're of no use to me. I'm sorry I wasted your time.
多谢你来，史考特
Thanks for coming in, Scottie.
好吧
Okay.
我…我不想这么难堪
I... I didn't mean to be that rough.
不，这听起来很蠢，我知道
No, it sounds idiotic, I know.
而你依然是那固执的苏格兰人 不是吗？
And you're still the hardheaded Scot, aren't you?
一直都是，你觉得我凭空捏造？
Always were. Do you think I'm making it up?
不
No.
我没有凭空捏造 我不知道如何捏造
I'm not making it up. I wouldn't know how.
她会告诉我一些事
She'll be talking to me about something.
突然，说到一半就没了
Suddenly, the words fade into silence.
她眼睛会变得迷蒙 然后空无一物
A cloud comes into her eyes and they go blank.
她到了别处，不再和我一起 成为我不认识的人
She's somewhere else, away from me, someone I don't know.
我呼唤她，她根本听不到
I call to her, she doesn't even hear me.
然后，长叹一声后，她回来了
Then, with a long sigh, she's back,
有神地看着我 甚至不知道自己出神过
looks at me brightly, doesn't even know she's been away.
无法告诉我是何时或何地
Can't tell me where or when.
那么，这多常发生？
Well, how often does this happen?
过去几周愈来愈频繁了
More and more in the past few weeks.
而且她会漫游 谁知道她漫游到哪儿去
And she wanders. God knows where she wanders.
有天我跟踪过她
I followed her one day,
看着她走出公寓 成为我不认识的人
watched her coming out of the apartment, someone I didn't know.
连走法都不一样
She even walked a different way.
她进到车子然后 开去金门大桥，8公里远
Got into her car and drove out to Golden Gate Park, five miles.
坐在湖边
Sat by the lake,
看着水面远处对岸的胖
staring across the water at the pillars that stand on the far shore.
你也知道，过去的门柱
You know, Portals of the Past.
坐好长一段时间 一动也不动
Sat there a long time, without moving.
我必须回办公室
I had to leave, get back to the office.
那晚我回家后 问她整天做了什么事
When I got home that evening, I asked her what she'd done all day.
她说她开车到金门大桥公园 坐在湖边，就这样
She said she'd driven out to Golden Gate Park and sat by the lake, that's all.
所以？
Well?
她车上的里程显示 她开了150公里
The speedometer on her car showed that she'd driven 94 miles.
她去了哪儿？
Where did she go?
史考特，我一定要知道 她去哪，做了什么
I've gotta know, Scottie, where she goes and what she does
我才要找医生
before I get involved with doctors.
你和医生谈过任何相关的事吗？
Well, have you talked to the doctors at all, about that?
有，但很谨慎
Yes, but carefully.
我想知道更多 才把她送去进行那种照护
I want to know more before committing her to that kind of care.
史考特…
Scottie...
好吧，我帮你找私家侦探 帮你跟踪她
All right, I'll get you a firm of private eyes to follow her for you.
这些人很可靠
They're dependable, good boys.
我只要你
I want you.
听着，这不是我的长项
Look, this isn't my line.
史考特，我要朋友 可以信任的人，我很怕这件事
Scottie, I need a friend, someone I can trust. I'm in a panic about this.
我早该退休了 我不想卷入这淌水
I'm supposed to be retired. I don't want to get mixed up in this darn thing.
听着，今晚我们要去歌剧首映
Look, we're going to an opening at the opera tonight.
我们先到恩尼用餐 你可以在那认出她
We're dining at Ernie's first. You can see her there.
恩尼
Ernie's.
“恩尼餐厅”
请问，能告诉我有关 坐在那儿的女性的事吗？
Say, will you tell me something about the lady sitting in there?
她观赏的画中女性是谁？
Who's the woman in the painting she's looking at?
那是卡洛塔
Oh, that's Carlotta.
目录里面有 《卡洛塔画像》
You'll find it in the catalog. Portrait of Carlotta.
- 能给我吗？ - 好
- May I have this? - Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
“麦基瑞克旅馆”
您好？
Yes?
我能帮您吗？
Is there something I can do for you?
- 是，这是你的旅馆？ - 是的
- Yes. You run this hotel? - Oh, yes.
能不能告诉我二楼角落 那个角落的房客是谁？
Would you tell me who has the room on the second floor in the corner, that corner?
噢，很抱歉我们不能提供 这种资讯
Oh, I'm afraid we couldn't give out information of that sort.
我们的客人有权利保有隐私 您知道的
Our clients are entitled to their privacy, you know.
而且这应该违法
And I do believe it's against the law.
当然，我想她们不会介意 但我还是…
Of course, I don't think any of them would mind,  really, but still I...
真是，她犯了什么错吗？
Oh, dear, has she done something wrong?
请回答我的问题
Please answer my question.
我无法想像 长得那么好看的甜美女孩…
I can't imagine that sweet girl with that dear face...
她叫什么？
What's her name?
法帝斯，法帝斯小姐 那种西班牙姓
Valdes. Miss Valdes. Spanish, you know.
卡洛塔法帝斯？
Carlotta Valdes?
正是
Yeah, that's it.
很甜美的名字吧？外国名，但甜美
Sweet name, isn't it? Foreign, but sweet.
她租下多久了？
How long has she had the room?
应该两周 她的租约明天到期
Oh, it must be two weeks. Her rent's due tomorrow.
她曾在这儿过夜吗？
Does she sleep here, ever?
不，她每周 只是过来坐个两三次
No, she just comes to sit two or three times a week.
我不问问题 只要她们表现良好的话
I don't ask questions, you know, as long as they're well-behaved.
但我不得说…
But I must say...
她下来的时候 别说我来过的事
When she comes down, don't say that I've been here.
噢，她今天没有来
Oh, but she hasn't been here today.
我五分钟前看到她进来
I just saw her come in five minutes ago.
不，她根本没出现
No, she hasn't been here at all.
我会看到她
Well, I would have seen her, you know.
我一直都在这儿 替我的塑胶植物叶子上油
I've been right here all the time, putting olive oil on my rubber plant leaves.
还有，你看到没？ 她的钥匙在架子上
And there. There, you see? Her key is on the rack.
能请你上去看看吗？
Well, would you please go up and look?
- 她房间？ - 没错
- To her room? - That's right.
当然行，你要求的话
Yes, of course, if you ask.
- 但似乎蛮傻的 - 多谢
- But it does seem silly. - Thank you.
警探先生？
Oh, Mr. Detective?
你能上来看一下吗？
Would you like to come and look?
她车子不见了
Her car's gone.
什么车？
What car?
蜜吉，你认识谁 是旧金山历史的权威？
Midge, who do you know that's an authority on San Francisco history?
女孩就喜欢这种招呼
That's the kind of greeting a girl likes.
不是“你看来真美”之类
None of this, "Hello, you look wonderful," stuff.
而是直接的 “你认识谁是旧金山历史的权威…”
Just a good straight, "Who do you know that's an authority on San Francisco..."
- 饮料？ - 不，谢了
- Want a drink? - No, thanks.
为何需要？你认识大家
Well, who do you? You know everybody.
桑德斯教授，在柏克莱
Professor Saunders, over in Berkeley.
不，不，不是那种历史
No, no, I don't mean that kind of history.
我指小事情 像是连你都不认识的人的消息
I mean the small stuff, you know, people you never heard of.
你是指老旧金山的 老放荡年代
Well, you mean the gay old bohemian days of gay old San Francisco.
八卦故事，像是1879年8月 谁枪杀了滨水区的谁
Juicy stories, like who shot who in the Embarcadero in August, 1879.
对，那种
Yeah, that's right.
- 派普李伯 - 谁？
- Pop Leibel. - Who?
派普李伯，大船书局的店长
Pop Leibel. He owns the Argosy Book Shop.
你想知道什么？
Why, what do you want to know?
我想知道1879年8月 是谁杀了滨水区的谁
I want to know who shot who in the Embarcadero in August, 1879.
等一下
Hey, wait a minute.
你不当警探了 这怎么回事？
You're not a detective anymore. What's going on?
- 你熟吗？ - 谁？
You know him well? Who?
- 派普李伯 - 当然
Pop Leibel. Oh, sure.
那来吧，我们走了 你帮我介绍，去拿帽子
Well, come on, let's go. I want you to introduce me. Get your hat.
我不用帽子
I don't need a hat.
强尼，这怎么回事？
Hey, Johnny, what's it all about?
嘿
Hey.
等一下
Wait a minute.
“大船书局”
噢，是的，我记得，卡洛塔
Hello. Yes, I remember. Carlotta.
美丽的卡洛塔
The beautiful Carlotta.
悲伤的卡洛塔
The sad Carlotta.
艾迪与格尔街角的老木屋
What does an old wooden house at the corner of Eddy and Gough Street
跟卡洛塔有何关系？
have to do with Carlotta Valdes?
那本来是她的 很多年前为了她盖的
Well, it was hers. It was built for her many years ago.
谁盖的？ 是…
- By whom? - By...
是…
By...
不行，名字，我记不起来了
No. The name, I do not remember.
是个有钱有势的男人
A rich man, a powerful man.
- 香烟？ - 不，谢了
- Cigarette? - No, thank you.
- 香烟，小姐？ - 不，谢了
- Cigarette, miss? - No, thanks.
这是耳熟 详的故事
It is not an unusual story.
她从哪个小地方来 到这座城的南部
She came from somewhere small to the south of the city.
有人说她来自传教殖民区
Some say from a mission settlement.
年轻，是的，非常年轻
Young, yes. Very young.
有人看到她在歌厅 和那个男人一起唱歌跳舞
And she was found dancing and singing in a cabaret by that man.
他占有了她 然后替她盖大房子
And he took her and built for her the great house
位在西扩增区
in the Western Addition.
然后有个…
And there was a...
有个孩子
There was a child.
对，这就对了，一个孩子
Yes, that's it. A child. A child.
无法准确地告诉你经过了多久时间
I cannot tell you exactly how much time passed,
或是当时有多少欢乐
or how much happiness there was.
但后来，他甩了她
But, then, he threw her away.
他没有孩子 他太太没生下孩子
He had no other children. His wife had no children.
所以他留下孩子，并甩了她
So he kept the child and threw her away.
要知道，那种时候 男人可以这样
You know, a man could do that in those days.
他们有权力也有特权
They had the power and the freedom.
她变成了悲伤的卡洛塔
And she became the sad Carlotta.
一个人在大房子里 一个人走在街上
Alone in the great house, walking the streets alone.
她的衣服变得又老 又补贴又脏
Her clothes becoming old and patched and dirty.
还有发疯的卡洛塔
And the mad Carlotta.
在街上拦住人，问道
Stopping people in the streets to ask,
“我孩子在哪？
"Where is my child?
“有看到我孩子吗？”
"Have you seen my child?"
可怜的人
Poor thing.
然后她死了
And she died.
- 她死了 - 怎么死？
- She died. - How?
自我了结
By her own hand.
这种故事很多
There are many such stories.
- 非常感谢你 - 不客气
- Well, thank you very much. - You are welcome.
我很感激，再见
I appreciate it. Good-bye.
再见
Good-bye.
喂，等一下！ 再见，派普，多谢了
Hey, wait a minute! Good-bye, Pop. Thanks a lot.
- 好了，强尼，付我钱 - 为了什么？
- Now then, Johnny-O, pay me. - For what?
带你过来，好了，快说
For bringing you here. Come on, tell.
没什么好说的
There's nothing to tell.
你快说，不然就让你穿束衣 好啦，强尼，拜托
You'll tell or you'll be back in that corset. Come on, Johnny, please.
来吧，我带你回家
Come on, come on. I'll take you home.
我们到了
There we are.
- 你没说全部 - 不，我说得够了
- You haven't told me everything. - No, I've told you enough.
男主角是谁？太太是谁？
Who's the guy and who's the wife?
出去，我有事要忙
Out. I've got things to do.
我懂了，打电话的人 你的大学旧友，艾斯特
I know. The one that phoned, your old college chum, Elster.
- 密吉，拜托出去 - 所以概念是
- Midge, out, please. - And the idea is
那个美丽又发疯的卡洛塔 回到阳间了
that the beautiful, mad Carlotta has come back from the dead
并且附身在艾斯特太太身上
and taken possession of Elster's wife.
噢，强尼，真是，别闹了
Now, Johnny, really. Come on.
我没告诉你我的想法 我说的是他的想法
Well, I'm not telling you what I think. I'm telling you what he thinks.
那你的想法是？
Well, what do you think?
这个，我…
Well, I...
- 她漂亮吗？ - 卡洛塔？
- Is she pretty? - Carlotta?
不，不是卡洛塔，艾斯特的太太
No, not Carlotta. Elster's wife.
是
Yes.
那我猜你觉得她…
I guess you'd consider that she would be...
我想我要看那幅画，再见
I think I'll go take a look at that portrait. Good-bye.
蜜吉…
Midge...
- 再见 - 密吉，你…
- Good-bye. - Midge, you...
做得很好，史考特 你的功夫很棒
You've done well, Scottie. You're good at your job.
- 那是卡洛塔法帝斯 - 是
- That's Carlotta Valdes. - Yes.
你没有告诉我全部
There are things you didn't tell me.
- 我不知道她会做些什么 - 但你知道这件事
- I didn't know where she'd lead you. - But you knew about this.
对
Oh, yeah.
你注意到她的发型吗？
You notice the way she does her hair?
要知道，还有其他部份
You know, there's something else.
我太太麦德琳 拥有几个卡洛塔的首饰
My wife, Madeleine, has several pieces of jewelry that belonged to Carlotta.
是她继承来的
She inherited them.
从没有戴过 因为样式太过老旧
Never wore them. They were too old-fashioned.
直到现在
Until now.
现在她独自一人时 会把首饰拿出来看
Now, when she's alone, she takes them out and looks at them,
小心又好奇的拿着
handles them gently, curiously.
戴上首饰 然后盯着镜子里的自己
Puts them on and stares at herself in the mirror.
飘到另一个世界去 又成了另一个人
And goes into that other world, is someone else again.
所以卡洛塔法帝斯是什么人？
Now, Carlotta Valdes was what?
你太太的祖母？
Your wife's grandmother?
曾祖母
Great-grandmother.
所以卡洛塔被带走的孩子
Now, the child who was taken from her,
让卡洛塔失心疯 最后造成她自杀的，是麦德琳祖母
whose loss drove Carlotta mad and to her death, was Madeleine's grandmother.
而麦基瑞克旅馆 是法帝斯家旧址
And the McKittrick Hotel is the old Valdes home.
这就说明一切了
Well, I think that explains it.
有这样的历史背景 任何人都可能变得过度狂热
Anyone could become obsessed with the past with a background like that.
她没听过卡洛塔法帝斯
She never heard of Carlotta Valdes.
她对多罗瑞教团的坟墓一无所知？
She knows nothing of a grave out at the Mission Dolores?
或是艾迪街上的老房子？那…
Or that old house on Eddy Street? The...
- 位在旧金山艺术博物馆的画像… - 都不知道
- The portrait at the Palace of the Legion of... - Nothing.
那当她去这些地方时…
Well, when she goes to these places...
她不再是我太太
She's no longer my wife.
你怎么知道这些 她不知道的事？
Well, how do you know all these things she doesn't?
她母亲过世前 告诉我大部份的事
Her mother told me most of them before she died.
其余都是我自己找出来的
I dug out the rest for myself here.
她为何不告诉女儿？
Why wouldn't she tell her daughter?
本能的恐惧
Natural fear.
她祖母后来疯了，自我了结
Her grandmother went insane, took her own life.
麦德琳也传承到了
Her blood is in Madeleine.
老兄，我需要你
Boy, I need this.
麦德琳
Madeleine.
麦德琳！
Madeleine!
是？
Yes?
不，没事
No, it's all right.
好，我会回电
Yeah, I'll call you back.
好
Yes.
你没事吗？
Are you all right?
噢，你的…
Oh. Oh, your...
可以穿这个
You'll want this.
你最好到火边来 比较温暖
You'd better come over here by the fire where it's warm.
我为何在这儿？
What am I doing here?
发生什么事？
What happened?
你掉入旧金山海湾
Well, you fell into San Francisco Bay.
我已经尽量吹干你头发了
And I tried to dry your hair as best I could.
你的东西在厨房
Your things are in the kitchen.
很快就会干了
They'll be dry in a few minutes.
过来火边
Come on over by the fire.
来，我找些靠垫
Here, I'll get you some cushions.
给你
There you are.
要咖啡吗？
Would you like to have some coffee?
来，最好喝一些 或是你想喝点
Here, you'd better have some. Or perhaps you'd like a drink.
我掉入海湾，你把我救上来？
I fell into the Bay and you fished me out?
没错
That's right.
谢谢
Thank you.
你不记得？
You don't remember?
不，我…
No, I...
你记得自己在哪吗？
You remember where you were?
当然，是的，我还记得
Why, yes. Yes, of course I remember that.
但是我可能有点头晕 然后昏倒了
But then I must have had a dizzy spell and fainted.
你本来在哪？
Where were you?
老堡垒尖，普西迪欧外面那儿
At old Fort Point, out at the Presidio.
我当然记得，我常常去那里
Of course, I remember. I often go there.
为什么？为何去那？
Why? Why do you go there?
因为我好喜欢那里 非常漂亮
Because I love it so. It's beautiful there,
尤其日落时
especially at sunset.
多谢你的炉火
Thank you for the fire.
你本来去哪？
Where were you before?
- 指何时？ - 今天下午
- When? - This afternoon, I mean.
到处晃
Wandering about.
我知道，去哪儿？ 你在那之前去哪儿？
I know, but where? Where were you just before?
市中心，逛街
Downtown, shopping.
来，再喝些咖啡 应该还很温暖
Here, you'd better have some coffee. I think it's still warm.
你的问题真是直接
You're terribly direct in your questions.
很抱歉，我不想这么鲁莽
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't mean to be rude.
你没有，你只是很直接
You're not. You're merely direct.
你在旧堡垒尖 当时做什么？
And what were you doing there, at old Fort Point?
噢，只是到处晃
Oh, just wandering about.
- 你也喜欢这样？ - 是
Oh, you like it too? Yes.
在那之前你去了哪里？
And where had you been just before?
我去了旧金山艺术博物馆 那个画廊
I'd been to the Palace of the Legion of Honor, the art gallery.
是的，真是个迷人的地方吧？
Oh, yes, that's a lovely spot, isn't it?
我没进去过 但是开车经过，看来好迷人
I've never been inside, but it looks so lovely driving past.
你当时到处晃 我真是幸运
It's lucky for me you were wandering about.
谢谢
Thank you.
我太打扰你了
I've been a terrible bother to you.
不，你没有
No, you haven't.
还有，当你…
Oh, when you...
我头发里有几个发簪
There were some pins in my hair.
发簪，是的，就在这里 我这就帮你拿
Oh, the pins, yes. Right in here. I'll get them for you.
还有皮包，麻烦了
And my purse, please.
给你
Here you are.
谢谢
Thank you.
要知道，你不该带我来这的
You shouldn't have brought me here, you know.
但我不知道你的住处
Well, I didn't know where you lived.
你可以找我车子里
You could have looked in my car.
不过，你不认得我的车，对吧？
Oh, but then, you didn't know my car, did you?
不，我知道是哪部 现在就在外头
No, I knew which one it was. It's right outside here now.
但我不觉得 你希望那个模样回家
But I didn't think you wanted to be taken home that way.
对，你说的对
No, you're right.
很高兴你没带我回家 我就不会认识你了
I'm glad you didn't take me home. I wouldn't have known you.
谢谢，但我不认识你 你也不认识我
Thank you. But I don't know you, and you don't know me.
我叫麦德琳艾斯特
My name is Madeleine Elster.
我叫约翰佛格森
My name's John Ferguson.
真是个好名字 你朋友叫你约翰或杰克？
Good, strong name. Do your friends call you John or Jack?
大部分是约翰
Oh, John, mostly.
老朋友叫我约翰 熟人则叫我史考特
Old friends call me John. Acquaintances call me Scottie.
那我叫你佛格森先生
I shall call you Mr. Ferguson.
噢，真是，我可不喜欢，不妙
Oh, gee whiz, I wouldn't like that. Oh, no.
经过下午这件事 我想你或许可以叫我史考特
And after what happened this afternoon, I should think maybe you'd call me Scottie.
或甚至约翰
Maybe even John.
我喜欢约翰
I prefer John.
那就这么说定了 你做什么的，约翰？
There, that's done. And what do you do, John?
到处晃
Wander about.
真是个好职业 而你住在这，独自一人？
That's a good occupation. And you live here, alone?
人们不该一个人住
One shouldn't live alone.
有些人却喜欢
Some people prefer it.
不，这是错的
No, it's wrong.
我已婚了
I'm married, you know.
能不能告诉我？
Will you tell me something?
你以前这样过吗？
Has this ever happened to you before?
什么？
What?
掉入旧金山海湾
Falling into San Francisco Bay.
噢
Oh.
不，不，没发生过
No. No, it's never happened before.
当我还是小女孩时 我曾经掉出小舟摔到湖里
Oh, I've fallen into lakes out of rowboats when I was a little girl.
我甚至摔进河流过 试着从一块石头跳到另一块
I even fell into the river once, trying to leap from one stone to another.
但我从未掉入旧金山海湾
But I've never fallen into San Francisco Bay.
你也有过吗？
Have you ever before?
不，这也是我的第一次
No, it's the first time for me, too.
来，我帮你加些咖啡
Here, I'll get you some more coffee.
喂？
Hello?
史考特，怎么了？ 她还没回家
Scottie, what happened? She's not home yet.
不，她没事，还在这 我很快就带她回家
No, she's all right. She's still here. I'll bring her home soon.
怎么了？
Oh, what happened?
她掉进海湾里
She went into the Bay.
喂？喂？
Hello? Hello?
有受伤吗？
Did she hurt herself?
没有，她没事 不用担心
No, she's going to be in fine shape. There's nothing to worry about.
但是她却不知道 现在，你了解了吗？
But she doesn't know. Now, do you understand that?
她不知道怎么回事
She doesn't know what happened.
史考特，麦德琳26岁了
Scottie, Madeleine is 26.
卡洛塔法帝斯在26岁的时候自杀
Carlotta Valdes committed suicide when she was 26.
先等一下，盖文
Just hold on a minute, Gavin.
好了，强尼，所以是鬼魂吗？
Well now, Johnny-O.  Was it a ghost?
好玩吗？
Was it fun?
那封信要给我？
That letter for me?
- 是，你好 - 你好
Yes. Hello. Hello.
我昨晚很担心你 你不该那样走掉
I worried about you last night. You shouldn't have run off that way.
我突然觉得自己很蠢
Well, I suddenly felt such a fool.
我本来想载你回家 你还好吗？
I wanted to drive you home. Are you all right?
噢，是的，我很好，没有后遗症
Oh, yes. Yes, I'm fine. No aftereffects.
但我如今回想 水很冰冷，对吧
But as I remember now, the water was cold, wasn't it?
可真是
It sure was.
你帮我的牺牲真大
What a terrible thing for me to do.
你人太好了
You were so kind.
这是个正式的感谢纸条 附上大大的道歉
It's a formal thank-you note and a great big apology.
你没什么好道歉的
Oh, you've nothing to apologize for.
当然有了
Oh, yes, I do.
这整件事对你来说 一定很窘
The whole thing must have been so embarrassing for you.
完全不会，我很喜欢
Not at all. I enjoyed
跟你聊天
talking to you.
其实，我也喜欢跟你聊天
Well, I enjoyed talking to you.
那，我来拿信
Well, I'll get my mail.
你要杯咖啡吗？
Would you like to have a cup of coffee?
不用，谢谢
No. No, thank you.
我无法邮寄 我不知道你的住址，但记得地标
Well, I couldn't mail it. I didn't know your address, but I had a landmark.
我记得科伊塔 凭着它就能找到你
I remembered Coit Tower. It led me straight to you.
这真是我第一次 想好好感谢科伊塔
Well, that's the first time I've been grateful for Coit Tower.
我也希望能
I hope we will, too.
- 什么？ - 再次见面
What? Meet again sometime.
现在就是
We have.
再见
Good-bye.
你要去哪？
Where are you going?
- 我不知道 - 逛街？
- Oh, I don't know. - Shopping?
不
No.
那有特定的目标吗？
Well, anywhere in particular?
不，我本来只想晃晃
No, I just thought that I'd wander.
我也正想这么做
Oh, that's what I was going to do.
噢是的，没错，我都忘了 这正是你的职业，不是吗？
Oh, yes, that's right. I forgot. It's your occupation, isn't it?
对，所以你不觉得有点浪费 我们两个…
Yeah, well, don't you think it's kind of a waste for the two of us...
各自晃？
- To wander separately? - Uh-huh.
只有一人才能闲晃
But only one is a wanderer.
两个人总会出现目的地
Two together are always going somewhere.
不，我不认为这是真的
No, I don't think that's necessarily true.
你的门没关
You left your door open.
马上回来
Be right back.
多老了？
How old?
约两千年或更久
Oh, some 2,000 years or more.
最长寿的生命
The oldest living things.
没错
Yes.
你没有来过此？
You've never been here before?
没有
No.
你在想什么？
What are you thinking?
那些出生了 然后又逝去的人
Of all the people who've been born and have died,
而这些树持续生长
while the trees went on living.
确实的名字是加州红木 “永远绿色，持续生长”
Their true name is Sequoia sempervirens. "Always green, ever living."
- 我不喜欢 - 为什么？
- I don't like them. - Why?
知道自己会死
Knowing I have to die.
这儿有个被砍下老树的剖面图
Here's a cross section of one of the old trees that's been cut down.
“1215年签署大宪章”
“1066年黑斯廷战争”
“西元909年”
“1492年发现美洲”
“1776年宣布独立”
“1930年树被砍下”
这儿的某处，我出生了
Somewhere in here, I was born,
那儿，我死了
and there I died.
对你来说只是一瞬间 你毫无所觉
It was only a moment for you. You took no notice.
麦德琳
Madeleine.
麦德琳，你现在身在哪儿？
Madeleine, where are you now?
- 和你一起 - 哪里？
- Here with you. - Where?
高大的树…
Tall trees...
你来过此吗？
Have you been here before?
- 是 - 何时？
- Yes. - When?
你何时出生的？
When were you born?
- 很久以前 - 哪里？
- Long ago. - Where?
何时？告诉我
When? Tell me.
- 麦德琳，告诉我 - 不！
- Madeleine, tell me. - No!
麦德琳告诉我是什么 你要去哪？
Madeleine, tell me what it is. Where do you go?
- 是什么带走你？ - 我不能说
- What takes you away? - No, I can't tell you.
你跳入海湾时 不知道自己身在何处
When you jumped into the bay, you didn't know where you were.
- 你猜过，其实不知道 - 我没跳
- You guessed, but you didn't know. - I didn't jump.
- 我没跳，你说我掉下去了 - 你为何跳？
- I didn't jump. I fell. You told me I fell. - Why did you jump?
- 你为何跳？ - 我不能说
- Why did you jump? - I can't tell you.
你为何跳？究竟有什么
Why did you jump? What was there inside
- 叫你跳下去？ - 不，拜托，拜托
- that told you to jump? - No, please. Please.
什么？什么？
What? What?
别再问我了，别再问我了 带我离开这里吧
Please don't ask me. Please don't ask me. Take me away from here.
要我带你回家吗？
Shall I take you home?
有光的地方
Somewhere in the light.
答应我 答应我你不再问了
Promise me something. Promise you won't ask me again.
拜托答应我
Please promise me that.
你为何跑？
Why did you run?
我要负责看着你
I'm responsible for you now.
要知道，中国人说过 你救过一个人的生命
You know, the Chinese say that once you've saved a person's life,
就永远要负起责任 所以我会负责
you're responsible for it forever, so I'm committed.
我必须知道
I have to know.
我知道的不多
There's so little that I know.
好像我正走下很长的长廊
It's as though I were walking down a long corridor
本来很多镜子 如今上面还有镜子的碎片
that once was mirrored, and fragments of that mirror still hang there.
当我到长廊的终点时
And when I come to the end of the corridor,
除了黑暗，空无一物
there's nothing but darkness.
我知道等我走入黑暗
And I know that when I walk into the darkness,
就是我的死期
that I'll die.
我从未走到终点 我总是在那之前就回神了
I've never come to the end. I've always come back before then.
除了一次
Except once.
昨天
Yesterday?
但你不知道
And you didn't know. You didn't know what happened
你不知道怎么了 直到醒来发现跟我一起
till you found yourself with me.
你不知道自己在哪
You didn't know where you were.
但是微小的画面 镜子的碎片，你还记得
But the small scenes, the fragments of the mirror, you remember those.
- 很模糊 - 你记得什么？
- Vaguely. - What do you remember?
有个房间，只有我一个人
There's a room, and I sit there alone.
- 总是一人 - 还有呢？
Always alone. What else?
- 坟墓 - 哪里？
A grave. Where?
不知道 是新挖的坟墓，我…
I don't know. It's an open grave and I...
我站在墓碑旁 向下看里面
I stand by the gravestone, looking down into it.
- 是我的墓 - 你怎么知道？
- It's my grave. - But how do you know?
我知道
I know.
墓碑上面有名字吗？
But is there a name on the gravestone?
不，不，它还崭新，等着刻字
No. No, it's new and clean and waiting.
还有呢？
Well, what else?
我想，这部份是梦境
This part is a dream. I think.
有个高塔 还有大钟，跟下面的花园
There's a tower, and a bell and a garden below.
好像在西班牙，是西班牙的村子
It seems to be in Spain, a village in Spain.
闪了一下，就没了
It clicks off and it's gone.
画像？
Well, a portrait?
- 看到画像吗？ - 没有
- Do you see a portrait? - No.
如果我能够找到钥匙 找到起源，全部拼在一起，我…
If I could just find the key, the beginning, and put it together, I...
如何，好好解释？
So, explain it away?
总有方式能解释的
There's a way to explain it, you see.
如果我疯了，就能解释清楚，对吧？
If I'm mad, then that would explain it, wouldn't it?
麦德琳！
Madeleine!
噢，史考特！
Oh, Scottie!
我没疯！我没疯！ 我不想死
I'm not mad! I'm not mad! I don't want to die.
我身体里有其他人 她说我必须死
There's someone within me, and she says I must die.
史考特，别放开我
Oh, Scottie, don't let me go.
我在这，我抓紧你了
I'm here. I've got you.
我好害怕
I'm so afraid.
别离开我
Don't leave me.
陪着我
Stay with me.
永远
All the time.
嗨，强尼
Hi, Johnny.
嗨
Hi.
收到我的讯息吗？
Did you get my message?
其实有
I did, indeed.
我帮你拿饮料
I'll get you a drink.
好
Okay.
你何时开始偷偷摸摸 把纸条塞在男人的门缝里？
Since when do you go around slipping notes under men's doors?
自从我不再用电话约他们后
Since I stopped being able to get them on the phone.
对于无所事事的人来说 你可真是个忙碌的家伙
For a man who has nothing to do, you're certainly a busy little bee.
你最近都上哪儿？
Where do you go these days?
只是晃晃
Just wandering.
到哪儿？
Where?
随意走
Round about.
噢
Oh.
到底是什么…
What was this...
为何这么急着要见我？
What was this desperate urge to see me?
我的纸条应该只写 “你在哪儿？”
All I said in my note was, "Where are you?"
我看并没有多急
Doesn't sound very desperate to me.
有，我感应到不安的情绪
Yeah, I detected a little undercurrent.
那，我只是想说如果 我请你喝东西，请你吃晚餐
Well, I just thought that if I gave you a drink and fed you some dinner,
你或许会感激 带我去看电影
you'd be so grateful, you'd take me to a movie.
这很公平 晚餐时要聊什么？
That's fair enough. What'll we talk about at dinner?
就这些那些
Oh, this and that.
我在做什么？
What I've been doing?
你想说的话
Only if you want to.
我肯定不会聊到 你不想谈的内容
I'm sure we won't talk about anything you don't want to talk about.
自然是的
Naturally.
你最近在做什么？
What have you been doing?
到处晃
Wandering.
你又做了什么？ 谢了，亲爱的
What have you been doing? Thank you, dear.
我有段美好的时光
Oh, I've been having a wonderful time.
我又回到初恋的对象 绘画
I've gone back to my first love, painting.
真不错
Well, good for you.
我总是说 你浪费时间在内衣部门里
I always said you were wasting your time in the underwear department.
要知道，这是生活 但这东西我真的很兴奋
You know, it's a living. But I'm really excited about this.
什么东西？静物画？
What is it? A still life?
不，不完全是，你要看吗？
No. No, not exactly. You wanna see?
好呀
Hmm. Yeah.
其实，我想或许会送你
Matter of fact, I thought I might give it to you.
哦？
Oh?
强尼！
Johnny!
这不好笑，蜜吉
It's not funny, Midge.
- 强尼！ - 不行
- Johnny! - No.
强尼，我只是想…
Johnny, I just thought...
不行
No.
我们改天再去看电影，好吗？
Let's make that movie some other night, okay?
强尼！
Johnny!
麦洁洛瑞伍德，你这傻子！
Oh, Marjorie Wood, you fool!
呆子！
Idiot!
真蠢！真蠢！真蠢！
Stupid! Stupid! Stupid!
麦德琳！怎么回事？几点了？
Madeleine! What's the matter? What time is it?
我该打给你的 但我想见你，想和你一起
I should have phoned you, but I wanted to see you and be with you.
为什么？怎么了？
Why? What's happened?
我做了个梦 那个梦又来了
I had the dream. The dream came back again.
好了，好了，一切都没事的
Now, now, it's gonna be all right.
会没事的 来，我给你些白兰地
It'll be all right. Here, I'll get you some brandy.
把它喝下去 来，就像服药一样
Just drink this down. Here, just like medicine.
好了
There now.
那只是梦，你现在清醒了 你现在没事了
It was a dream. You're awake. You're all right now.
好了，能告诉我吗？
Now, can you tell me?
又是那座塔，还有大钟 以及老式的西班牙村落
It was the tower again, and the bell, and the old Spanish village.
是？
Yes?
很清晰，第一次如此的清晰 全部内容
Clear, so very clear for the first time. All of it.
告诉我
Tell me.
是个村落广场，有着树木
It was a village square and a green with trees,
有个老旧的白漆西班牙式教堂 以及修道院
and an old whitewashed Spanish church with a cloister.
树木后面 有个又大又灰的木屋
Across the green, there was a big, gray, wooden house,
它有门廊和百叶窗 上面还有阳台跟小花园
with a porch and shutters and a balcony above, a small garden,
旁边是个马厩谷仓
and next to it a livery stable
里面排列着老旧的马车
with old carriages lined up inside.
继续
Go on.
到树木底端 有个白漆的石屋
At the end of the green, there was a whitewashed stone house,
角落还有胡椒树
with a lovely pepper tree at the corner.
还有老加州风情的旧木制旅馆？
And an old wooden hotel from the old California days?
还有老式酒吧？ 阴暗、矮天花板、悬吊着油灯？
And a saloon? Dark, low ceilings, with hanging oil lamps?
是
Yes.
这全都存在，这不是梦
It's all there. It's no dream.
你以前去过，你以前看过
You've been there before. You've seen it.
不，从没
No, never.
麦德琳，在旧金山南方 160公里远处
Madeleine, a hundred miles south of San Francisco,
有个旧西班牙殖民地
there's an old Spanish mission,
叫做山璜保提斯塔 它还保留着
San Juan Bautista it's called, and it's been preserved
一百年前的模样 现在是博物馆
exactly as it was 100 years ago, as a museum.
现在好好想，亲爱的，好好想
Now, think hard, darling. Think hard.
你去过那儿，你以前看过
You've been there before. You've seen it.
不，不，我从未…我没去过那儿
No, no, I've never... I've never been there.
史考特，到底是什么？我没去过
Oh, Scottie, what is it? I've never been there.
好好想，现在回想你的梦境
Think hard. Now go on about your dream.
是什么让你如此害怕？
What was it that frightened you so?
我独自站在树林里 想寻找某个东西
I stood alone on the green searching for something.
然后我开始走向教堂
And then I started to walk to the church.
但是黑暗包围了我 我又孤单地在黑暗中
But then the darkness closed in and I was alone in the dark.
因为被卷入黑暗 所以我挣扎醒来
Being pulled into the darkness, and I fought to wake up.
你会没事的，麦德琳
Oh, you're going to be all right now, Madeleine.
你没发现吗？ 如今我有东西可以拼凑了
Don't you see? You've given me something to work on now.
我要带你到那个殖民地 这个下午去
I'm going to take you down there to that mission, this afternoon.
你看到之后 就会记得自己以前看过
And when you see it, you'll remember when you saw it before,
这能终结你的梦境 可以摧毁它，我保证，好吗？
and it'll finish your dream. It'll destroy it. I promise you. All right?
来吧，我带你回家
Come on now. I'll take you home.
不，我没事的
No. I'll be all right.
你大约中午再过来
You come back here around noon.
“马厩谷仓”
麦德琳，你现在位在何处？
Madeleine, where are you now?
- 和你一起 - 这全是真实的
- Here with you. - And it's all real.
彷佛就像是一百年前 或是一年前
It's not merely as it was 100 years ago, or a year ago,
或半年前 或你以前曾经来过时的模样
or six months ago, or whenever it was you were here to see it.
现在，麦德琳 回想你以前来这里的时候
Now, Madeleine, think of when you were here.
那时没这么多马车
There were not so many carriages then.
马厩里有很多马
There were horses in the stalls.
一只枣红、两只黑色、一只灰色
A bay, two black and a gray.
我最爱这儿
It was our favorite place.
但我们不能来这里玩
But we were forbidden to play here.
泰瑞莎修女会斥责我们
Sister Teresa would scold us.
看这个，这是你的灰马
Look at this. Well, here's your gray horse.
可能需要推几下 才能够顺利进出马厩
Have a little trouble getting in and out of the stall without being pushed,
就算如此…
but even so...
你瞧？这一切都有答案
You see? There's an answer for everything.
麦德琳，再试一下
Madeleine, try.
为了我试试看
Try for me.
我爱你，麦德琳
I love you, Madeleine.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
太迟了，太迟了
Too late. Too late.
不，不，我们在一起
No, no, we're together.
不，太迟了 有件事我必须做
No, it's too late. There's something I must do.
不，没有你必须做的事
No. There's nothing you must do.
你没有必须做的事
There's nothing you must do.
你没有被附身 你和我一起很安全
No one possesses you. You're safe with me.
不，太迟了
No, it's too late.
看，这不公平，太迟了
Look. It's not fair. It's too late.
不该这样的 这不该发生的
It wasn't supposed to happen this way. It shouldn't have happened.
注定会发生，我们相爱 这是最重要的
It had to happen. We're in love. That's all that counts.
- 让我走，请让我走！ - 听我说，听我说
- Look, let me go. Please let me go! - Listen to me. Listen to me.
你相信我爱你吗？
You believe I love you?
相信
Yes.
如果你失去我，你要知道我…
And if you lose me, then you'll know I...
我爱你 我想要一直爱着你
I loved you and I wanted to go on loving you.
我不会失去你
I won't lose you.
让我到教堂里，一个人
Let me go into the church, alone.
为什么？
But why?
麦德琳！
Madeleine!
佛格森
Ferguson.
艾斯特先生，他怀疑 自己太太的精神状况并不佳
Mr. Elster, suspecting that all was not well with his wife's mental state,
因此采取防范措施 请佛格森先生监视她
took the preliminary precaution of having her watched by Mr. Ferguson,
避免她发生危险
lest any harm befall her.
而您已听说 艾斯特先生准备要
And you have heard that Mr. Elster was prepared
把太太送到诊所里面
to take his wife to an institution,
让合格的专家 能够照顾她的精神状况
where her mental health would have been in the hands of qualified specialists.
佛格森先生，身为前警探
Mr. Ferguson, being an ex-detective,
应该是监视并保护对方的适当人选
would have seemed the proper choice for the role of watchdog and protector.
但您如今也知道 这是个不幸的选择
As you have learned, it was an unfortunate choice.
但我认为 您也同意丈夫并没有责任
However, I think you'll agree that no blame can be attached to the husband.
他延迟将太太送去医疗照护
His delay in putting his wife under medical care was due
是因为想知道更多 有关她行为的资讯
only to the need for information as to her behavior,
而他预期能自佛格森先生取得
which he expected to get from Mr. Ferguson.
他已采取任何 可保护太太的预防措施
He had taken every precaution to protect his wife.
但他无法预料 佛格森先生的弱点
He could not have anticipated that Mr. Ferguson's weakness,
他的惧高症
his fear of heights,
会在最需要他时 使他无能为力
would make him powerless when he was most needed.
至于佛格森先生
As to Mr. Ferguson,
您已经自他的前任长官 来自旧金山的
you have heard his former superior, Detective Captain Hansen,
汉生警探长得知
from that great city to the north,
他证实了佛格森的人格与能力
testify as to his character and ability.
汉生队长最为热心
Captain Hansen was most enthusiastic.
事实上在过去 曾经在类似的情况下
The fact that once before, under similar circumstances,
佛格森让一名警察同事摔死
Mr. Ferguson allowed a police colleague to fall to his death,
汉生队长称其为 “不幸的事件”
Captain Hansen dismissed as an "unfortunate incident."
当然，要赞赏佛格森先生
Of course, Mr. Ferguson is to be congratulated
曾经救过该女性一次
on having once saved the woman's life,
当时因为陷入心理失常状态 她跳入了海湾中
when, in a previous fit of aberration, she threw herself into the Bay.
很遗憾在他已得知 她的自杀倾向之后
It is a pity that knowing her suicidal tendencies,
第二次发生时 却没有更尽力些
he did not make a greater effort the second time.
但是我们不是来此
But we are not here to pass judgment
评断佛格森先生的被动态度 他什么都没做
on Mr. Ferguson's lack of initiative. He did nothing.
而法律对于没有做的事 并没有多少的规定
And the law has little to say on the subject of things left undone.
而他在看到对方坠落后的奇特行为
Nor does his strange behavior after he saw the body fall
也不该影响您的判决
have any bearing on your verdict.
他没有留在命案现场 他逃走了
He did not remain at the scene of the death. He left.
他声称发生了心理上的 意识不清，因此什么都不知道
He claims he suffered a mental blackout and knew nothing more
直到发现自己 几小时后已经返回
until he found himself back in his own apartment in San Francisco
位在旧金山的公寓里
several hours later.
您可以决定是否接受此理由
You may accept that, or not.
或是相信因为再次目睹 自己促使某人死亡
Or you may believe that having once again allowed someone to die,
他无法面对自己弱点 所造成的悲惨下场
he could not face the tragic result of his own weakness
因此逃走了
and ran away.
这不该影响您的判决
That has nothing to do with your verdict.
这要由他和他自己的良知去评断
It is a matter between him and his own conscience.
现在，从麦德琳艾斯特 死亡前的精神状况
Now, from the evidence of the state of mind of Madeleine Elster
还有她的死法
prior to her death, from the manner of her death,
以及法医验尸后出示的确切死因
and from the postmortem examination of the body
所得到的证据
showing the actual cause of her death,
您在达成判决上 应该没有困难，先生们
you should have no difficulty in reaching your verdict, gentlemen.
若要离席也请便
You may retire if you wish.
等一下，琼斯先生
Hold on, Mr. Jones.
- 我们得出判决了 - 谢谢
We've reached a verdict. Thank you.
“陪审团了解 麦德琳艾斯特会自杀
"The jury finds that Madeleine Elster committed suicide
“是因为神智不清”
"while of unsound mind."
您的判决将如此记录，解散
Your verdict will be so recorded. Dismissed.
好了，史考特，走吧
All right, Scottie, let's go.
我可以和他说几句吗？
Mind if I speak to him for a minute?
请便
No, go ahead.
史考特
Scottie.
抱歉，史考特，这真过分
Sorry, Scottie. That was rough.
他没权利这样说你
He had no right to speak to you like that.
这是我的错 我不该把你牵扯进来
It was my responsibility. I shouldn't have got you involved.
不用，你什么都不用说
No, there's nothing you have to say to me.
我要走了，史考特，不再回来
I'm getting out, Scottie, for good.
我不能待在这
I can't stay here.
我要把自己和她的事结清 然后走得越远越好
I'm going to wind up her affairs and mine, get away as far as I can.
或许欧洲 我可能再也不会回来
Europe, perhaps. And I probably never will come back.
再见，史考特
Good-bye, Scottie.
看有什么是我离开前 能替你做的
If there's anything I can do for you before I go.
他们绝对无法了解
There was no way for them to understand.
我们两个清楚 是谁杀了麦德琳
You and I know who killed Madeleine.
来吧，史考特，快离开吧
Come on, Scottie. Let's get out of here.
这是沃夫冈阿玛迪斯莫札特
It's Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus.
我跟从事音乐疗法的女性 谈了很久，强尼
I had a long talk with that lady in musical therapy, Johnny,
她说莫札特最适合你
and she says that Mozart's the boy for you,
能把陈年旧物一一扫掉
the broom that sweeps the cobwebs away.
起码那女性是这么说的
Well, it's what the lady said.
你知道吗，现在能这样录下来 真是太完美了，约翰
You know, it's wonderful how they have it all taped now, John.
我有治嗜酒症的音乐
I have music for dipsomaniacs,
还有治忧郁症的音乐 治臆想病的音乐
and music for melancholiacs, and music for hypochondriacs.
如果有人把音乐全搞混了 不知道会怎样
I wonder what would happen if somebody got their files mixed up.
我买了很多其他东西 你可以看看是否中意
I brought a lot of other things, and you can see what you like.
会自动关闭
It shuts off automatically.
噢，强尼，强尼 请认真试，再试试，强尼
Oh, Johnny. Johnny, please try. Try, Johnny.
你并未迷失，妈妈在这儿
You're not lost. Mother is here.
时间到了？
Time?
好的
Okay.
我会再来，约翰
I'll be in again, John.
要我关掉吗？
You want me to shut that off?
噢，强尼
Oh, John-O.
你甚至不知道我来了，是吧？
You don't even know I'm here, do you?
但我在这里
But I'm here.
护士，我可以见医生吗？
Nurse, could I see the doctor for a moment?
医生，伍德小姐
Doctor, Miss Wood.
能请你进来吗？
Won't you go in, please?
是，伍德小姐？
Yes, Miss Wood?
医生，你还需要多久 才能让他恢复正常？
Doctor, how long is it going to take you to pull him out of this?
这很难说 最少六个月，可能要一年
Well, it's hard to say. At least six months. Perhaps a year.
这真的要看他
It really could depend on him.
他不说话
He won't talk.
对，他患了严重的精神忧郁症
No. He's suffering from acute melancholia,
又加上罪恶感
together with a guilt complex.
那名女性的遭遇 使他深深自责
He blames himself for what happened to the woman.
我们…我们对于过去发生的事 所知很少
We... We know little of what went on before.
我可以告诉你一件事 他爱上了她
Well, I can give you one thing. He was in love with her.
噢，这确实让问题更复杂了 可不是？
Oh, that does complicate the problem, doesn't it?
我可以再雪上加霜
I can give you another complication,
他依然爱她
he still is.
医生，你还知道吗？
And you want to know something, Doctor?
我不觉得莫札特帮得上忙
I don't think Mozart's going to help at all.
你怎么有这部车？
Where'd you get this car?
- 什么？ - 这…这台车？
- I beg your pardon? - This... This car?
噢，我从以前住这儿 这个公寓的人买下的
Why, I bought it from a man who used to live here, in this apartment building,
盖文艾斯特先生 他搬家时，我向他买的
Mr. Gavin Elster. I bought it from him when he moved away.
你认识他还有那位太太
Oh, you knew him and his wife.
可怜的人，我不认识她
The poor thing. I didn't know her.
告诉我，她是不是真的…
Tell me, is it true that she really...
我…我很抱歉
I'm... I'm sorry.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Good evening. - Good evening.
给我威士忌和苏打，麻烦了
Give me a scotch and soda, will you.
究竟有什么事？
Well, what is it?
我可以问几个问题吗？
Could I ask you a couple of questions?
为什么？你是谁？
What for? Who are you?
我是约翰佛格森
My name is John Ferguson.
盖洛普民意调查？
Is this some kind of Gallup poll?
不是
Oh, no.
我想问几个问题
- There are just couple of things I'd like to ask. - You live in this hotel?
你住这间旅馆？
不，我刚好看到你走进来 所以我想…
No. I happened to see you when you came in, so I thought...
我猜也是，想搭讪
Yeah, I thought so. A pickup.
你真有胆子 跟着我进旅馆到我房间来
Well, you've got a nerve, following me right into the hotel and up to my room.
你快走，现在快走吧
Now, you beat it. Go on and beat it.
不，拜托，拜托 我只想和你说话
No, please, please. I just want to talk to you.
听着，我要喊人了
Listen, I'm gonna yell in a minute.
听好，我不会伤害你 真的，我保证
Listen, I'm not gonna hurt you. Honest. I promise.
拜托，让我和你说话
Please. Just let me talk to you.
- 谈什么？ - 你
- What about? - You.
为何？
Why?
你让我想起某人
Because you remind me of somebody.
这种理由我也听过
I heard that one before, too.
我让你想起某个 你以前疯狂爱上的人
I remind you of someone you used to be madly in love with,
然后她甩了你另结新欢
but then she ditched you for another guy,
自此之后 你就忘不了她
and you've been carrying the torch ever since.
接着你看到我就燃起情愫了
Then you saw me and something clicked.
你快猜到了
Well, you're not far wrong.
这对我没用，所以你快走吧
Well, it's not gonna work, so you better go.
拜托，让我进去
Please, let me come in.
门可以开着 我只想和你说话，拜托
You can leave the door open. I just want to talk to you. Please.
好吧，我先警告 我喊起来很大声的
Well, I warn you, I can yell awful loud.
你不需要喊人
Now, you won't have to.
反正，你看起来也不像 开膛手杰克，你想知道什么？
Well, you don't look very much like Jack the Ripper. What do you want to know?
- 我想知道你的名字 - 茱蒂巴顿
- I want to know your name. - Judy Barton.
- 你是谁？ - 只是个女孩，在玛格商店工作
- Who you are? - I'm just a girl. I work at Magnin's.
不对，那你怎么会住在这里呢？
No, but, how do you happen to be living here?
这里可以住，就这样
It's a place to live, that's all.
不是，你才住一阵子？
No, but you haven't lived here long?
对，大约三年
Yeah, about three years.
你以前住哪？
Well, where did you live before?
堪萨斯州盐水城
Salina, Kansas.
听着，这怎么回事？ 你想要什么？
Listen, what is this? What do you want?
我只想知道你是谁
I just want to know who you are.
我已经说了
Well, I told you.
我叫朱蒂巴顿 我来自堪萨斯州盐水城
My name is Judy Barton. I come from Salina, Kansas.
我在玛格商店工作，我住这儿
I work at Magnin's, and I live here.
我的天，一定要证明吗？
My gosh, do I have to prove it?
好了，先生，我的堪萨斯州驾照
All right, mister, my Kansas driver's license.
茱蒂巴顿，号码是2296794
Judy Barton, number Z296794,
堪萨斯州盐水城 枫树大道425号
425 Maple Avenue, Salina, Kansas.
看到上面的住址吗？ 正是这里的住址
See the address on this one? It's this place right here.
1954年5月25日发行的加州证照
A California license issued May 25, 1954.
你要检查我的指纹吗？ 满意了吗？
You want to check my thumbprints? You satisfied?
不论你是否满意 你该走了
And whether you're satisfied or not, you can just beat it.
你真的很煎熬，是吧？
Gee, you have got it bad, haven't you?
我这么像她吗？
Do I really look like her?
她…她死了，是吧？
She's... She's dead, isn't she?
很抱歉，抱歉我这么对你大叫
I'm sorry. And I'm sorry I yelled at you.
对，那是我和我的母亲
Yes, that's me with my mother.
那是我父亲，他死了
And that's my father. He's dead.
我母亲再嫁 但我不喜欢那个人
My mother married again, but I didn't like the guy,
所以我决定 来瞧瞧春光明媚的加州
so I decided I'd see what it's like in sunny California.
我已经来三年了
I've been here three years.
真的
Honest.
能和我吃晚餐吗？
Will you have dinner with me?
为什么？
Why?
我只是觉得经过这些 我好像亏欠什么
Well, I just feel that I owe you something after all this.
你没欠我什么
You don't owe me anything.
那你愿意吗？为了我的话？
Well, then will you? For me?
晚餐跟什么？
Dinner and what else?
就晚餐
Just dinner.
因为我很像她？
'Cause I remind you of her?
因为我想和你吃晚餐
Because I'd like to have dinner with you.
好吧，我也曾经 未曾见面直接约会过
Well, I've been on blind dates before.
其实，说真的 我也曾经见面就直接约会
Matter of fact, to be honest, I've been picked up before.
好的
Okay.
好，我去取车 我半小时后回来接你
All right, I'll get my car. I'll be back for you in half an hour.
噢，不行 你最好给我些时间换装整容一下
Oh, no, you better give me time to change and get fixed up.
一小时？
An hour?
可以
- Uh-huh. - Okay.
亲爱的史考特
Dearest Scottie.
你还是找到我了
And so you found me.
这是我最期盼 也最希望的时刻
This is the moment that I dreaded and hoped for.
想着如果又遇见你 我该说什么、做什么
Wondering what I would say and do if I ever saw you again.
我真的好想再见到你 一次也好
I wanted so to see you again, just once.
我现在要离开 你就可以放弃寻找了
Now I'll go, and you can give up your search.
我希望你能获得平静
I want you to have peace of mind.
你真的不用自责
You've nothing to blame yourself for.
你是受害者
You were the victim.
我只是工具，而你是 盖文艾斯特计划谋杀太太的受害者
I was the tool, and you were the victim of Gavin Elster's plan to murder his wife.
他选择我来扮演 因为我长得像她，他让我打扮得像她
He chose me to play the part because I looked like her. He dressed me up like her.
这么做很安全 因为她住在乡下，很少到城里来
It was quite safe because she lived in the country and rarely came to town.
他选择你成为自杀事件的目击者
He chose you to be the witness to a suicide.
卡洛塔故事是部分真实 部分捏造的
The Carlotta story was part real, part invented,
为了让你证实 麦德琳想要自杀
to make you testify that Madeleine wanted to kill herself.
他知道你的症状 他知道你绝对无法走上高塔的楼梯
He knew of your illness. He knew you'd never get up the stairs to the tower.
他设计得好精巧，完全没有误差
He planned it so well. He made no mistakes.
我犯了错，我坠入爱河
I made the mistake. I fell in love.
这不属于计划的内容
That wasn't part of the plan.
我还是爱着你 我也希望你能爱我
I'm still in love with you, and I want you so to love me.
如果我有勇气 我就会留下来继续隐瞒
If I had the nerve, I'd stay and lie,
希望我能让你再爱上我
hoping that I could make you love me again
爱上我本人
as I am for myself.
然后忘记麦德琳，忘记过去
And so forget the other and forget the past.
但我不知道 自己是否有勇气尝试
But I don't know whether I have the nerve to try.
来，来，让我用
Oh, here. Here, I'll do it.
好了
There you are.
再次谢了，晚安
Thanks again. Good night.
明天能见你吗？
Can I see you tomorrow?
明晚？
Tomorrow night? Well...
不，我指明天早上
No, I mean tomorrow morning.
但我要上班，我有工作
But I have to go to work. I've got a job.
别上班
Don't go to your job.
那我靠什么活？德州的油井？
And what'll I live on? My oil wells in Texas?
让我照顾你，茱蒂
Let me take care of you, Judy.
非常感谢，但不用了
Thanks very much, but no thanks.
不，茱蒂，你不了解
No, Judy, you don't understand.
我可是很清楚
Oh, I understand, all right.
我从17岁就很清楚了
I've been understanding since I was 17.
- 接下来做什么？ - 不，不
- And the next step is? - No, no. No, no.
不？不然是什么？
No? Then what?
我们可以常常见面
We could just see a lot of each other.
为何？
Why?
我让你想起她？
'Cause I remind you of her?
这不是赞美
It's not very complimentary.
没其他了？
And nothing else?
没有
No.
这也不是赞美
That's not very complimentary, either.
我只想尽量地和你在一起，茱蒂
I just want to be with you as much as I can, Judy.
我猜早上可以打电话 跟商店说一声
Well, I guess I could phone the store in the morning
给个藉口
and make some excuse.
给你
There you are.
我喜欢这个
I like that one.
喜欢这个？
Like that?
- 是 - 好的
- Yes. - All right.
这真不错
Well, that's very nice.
好漂亮
It's beautiful.
给你
There we are.
我们用好这个 就帮你买些衣服
Now, we'll get this, and then we'll buy you those clothes.
- 真的？ - 就在那边的蓝琪荷夫店
- Honest? - Right over there's Ransohoffs.
那儿最棒，这个多少？
It's the best. How much is that?
50分钱，多谢
That'll be 50 cents. Thank you.
史考特，不用如此
Scottie, you don't have to.
但我想
But I want to.
“蓝琪荷夫店”
不，不是这个，一点也不像
No, that's not it. Nothing like it.
但您说灰色，先生
But you said gray, sir.
听好 我只想要普通简洁的灰色套装
Now, look. I just want an ordinary, simple gray suit.
但我喜欢那件，史考特
But I like that one, Scottie.
不，不，这不对
No, no. It's not right.
这位先生知道自己在找什么
Gentleman seems to know what he wants.
好，我们会找到的
All right. We'll find it.
你在做什么？
Scottie, what are you doing?
我想替你买套装
I'm trying to buy you a suit.
但…但我喜欢她穿的第二套
But... But I love the second one she wore.
而这套，好漂亮
And this one, it's beautiful.
不，不，全都不对
No, no. They're none of them right.
我应该知道您指的套装 我们前阵子还有
Oh, I think I know the suit you mean. We had it some time ago.
让我找找看 或许还留有那个款式
Let me go and see. We may still have that model.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在找她穿过的套装 要给我穿
You're looking for the suit that she wore, for me.
你要我打扮像她
You want me to be dressed like her.
茱蒂，我只想你好看
Judy, I just want you to look nice.
我知道什么样的套装 最适合你
I know the kind of suit that'd look well on you.
不，不，我不要穿！
Oh, no. No, I won't do it!
茱蒂
Judy.
茱蒂，这对你应该 没多大影响，我只想看…
Judy, it can't make that much difference to you. I just want to see...
不，我不想试衣服 我什么都不要，我只想离开这儿
No, I don't want any clothes. I don't want anything. I want to get out of here.
茱蒂，拜托为了我
Judy, do this for me.
请看
Here we are.
对，就是它
Yes, that's it.
我想也是
I thought so.
- 我不喜欢 - 不，我要买下
- I don't like it. - No, we'll take it.
衣服合身吗？
Will the thing fit?
是的，可能需要些微的修改 但这是夫人的尺寸
Well, yes. It might need some slight alterations, but it's madam's size.
好了，亲爱的 我们不久后就能让您试穿了
All right, dear. We'll have it for you to try on in a moment.
修改需要多久？
How long will the alterations take?
这…
Well...
今晚可以拿吗？
May we have it by tonight?
如果一定要的话
Well, if it's absolutely necessary.
对，一定要 我们还想看晚宴服，晚礼服
Yes, it is. Now, we'd like to look at a dinner dress, an evening dress.
短裙、黑色，长袖 还有点方领
Short, black, with long sleeves, and a kind of square neck.
史考特！
Scottie!
哦！您非常清楚自己要什么，先生 我们会找找看
My! You certainly do know what you want, sir. I'll see what we have.
好，就是它 这件有棕色吗？
All right. That's it. Do you have them in brown?
- 是，有的 - 很好
- Yes, we have. - Fine.
来，茱蒂 直接喝下，就像服药
Here, Judy. Drink this straight down, just like medicine.
住手
Stop.
为何要这样？这有什么用？
Why are you doing this? What good will it do?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不知道 没用，我想，我不知道
I don't know. No good, I guess. I don't know.
真希望你没找到我 我想跑得远远的
I wish you'd leave me alone. I want to go away.
你可以，你知道的
You can, you know.
不，你不会让我走
No. You wouldn't let me.
而且我也不想走
And I don't wanna go.
茱蒂，茱蒂，我只想说
Oh, Judy. Judy, I tell you this.
过去几天，是我这一年来 第一次的快乐时光
These past few days have been the first happy days I've known in a year.
这我知道，因为…
I know. I know because...
我让你想起她
'Cause I remind you of her.
而且光想起还不够
And not even that very much.
不，不，茱蒂 茱蒂，你也是一部份
No. No, Judy. Judy, it's you, too.
你的某些地方…
There's something in you that...
你甚至不想碰我
You don't even want to touch me.
有，有，我想
Yes. Yes, I do.
你难道不能喜欢我 就我自己，现在的样子？
Couldn't you like me, just me, the way I am?
我们刚开始的时候 感觉很好，我们很愉快
When we first started out, it was so good. We had fun.
然后…然后你开始 要求这些衣服
And... And then you started in on the clothes.
如果你要的话 我会穿那该死的衣服
Well, I'll wear the darned clothes if you want me to,
只要你能喜欢我
if you'll just like me.
你的发色
The color of your hair.
不
Oh, no.
茱蒂，拜托，这应该没什么
Judy, please. It can't matter to you.
如果…
If...
如果我让你改变我，这样行吗？
If I let you change me, will that do it?
如果我照你说的去做
If I do what you tell me,
你会爱我吗？
will you love me?
会
Yes.
- 会 - 好吧
- Yes. - All right.
好吧，那我就照做 我再也不在乎原来的自己了
All right, then, I'll do it. I don't care anymore about me.
来，来吧，我们到火边坐
Here, come on. We'll sit by the fire.
恐怕这要花上几小时
I'm afraid it's going to take several hours.
年轻的小姐认为你或许该回家
The young lady thought perhaps you'd like to go home.
等到她完成 她就会立刻过去
And then she'll come there as soon as she's finished.
不用，你告诉她我会去她的旅馆 在那儿等她
Well, no. You tell her I'll go to her hotel and wait for her there.
发色你很肯定？
Oh, and you're sure about the color of the hair?
是的，这颜色很好用
Oh, yes. It's an easy color.
- 还有其他… - 是，先生，我们知道你要的
- And all the rest of... - Yes, sir, we know what you want.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么？
Well?
头发应该在脸后 然后束在脖子后面
It should be back from your face and pinned at the neck.
我这样说的 我也告诉你了
I told her that. I told you that.
我们试过，但似乎不适合我
We tried it. It just didn't seem to suit me.
拜托，茱蒂
Please, Judy.
晚餐去哪吃？
Where shall we go for dinner?
都可以
Anywhere you like.
恩尼？
Ernie's?
你很喜欢恩尼，对吧
You have a thing about Ernie's, don't you?
毕竟那是我们的纪念处
Well, after all, it's our place.
嗨，吾爱，喜欢吗？
Hello, my love. Like me?
你只有这点能耐？
Is that the best you can do?
过来
Come here.
不行，你会弄乱
Oh, no. You'll muss me.
其实，我正这么想 好了，过来
Well, that's what I had in mind. Now, come here.
太迟了，我画好妆了
It's too late. I got my face on.
而且我突然饿了 你要去其他地方吗？
And I'm suddenly hungry. Would you rather go somewhere else?
不，不，恩尼很好
No, no. Ernie's is fine.
我想要…
I'm gonna have...
我想要它又大又棒的牛排
I'm gonna have one of those big, beautiful steaks.
让我想想，前菜的话，我要…
Let me see. To start, I think I'll...
能帮我用一下吗？
Help me with this, will you?
我拿好了
I have it.
这个怎么用？
How do you work this thing?
看不出来吗？
Can't you see?
好，用好了
Oh. Now, there you are.
谢谢，我都好了
Thank you. I'm just about ready.
我只需要上个屑膏
All I've got to do is find my lipstick.
我放在哪？刚刚还在的
Where did I put it? I had it a minute ago.
是不是在这，找到了
I wonder if it's here. Here it is.
好，我可以了
There, I'm ready.
但首先，稍微把我弄乱？
But first, muss me a little?
史考特，你是爱我的，对吧？
Scottie, I do have you now, don't I?
我们要不要到其他地方吃晚餐？
How would you like to go someplace out of town for dinner?
或许可以开到南方去
Maybe we could drive down the peninsula.
好，你想要的话
All right. If you'd like.
我们走了好远
We're going awfully far.
我突然想好好开车 你很饿吗？
I just feel like driving. You terribly hungry?
不，不，没关系
No. No, it's all right.
你要去哪？
Where're you going?
还有最后一件事
One final thing I have to do.
然后，我就摆脱过去了
And then, I'll be free of the past.
史考特，我们为何来这？
Scottie, why are we here?
我说过了
I told you.
我必须再回到过去一次
I have to go back into the past once more.
再一次，就最后一次
Just once more, for the last time.
为什么？为什么是这里？
Why? Why here?
麦德琳死在这儿，茱蒂
Madeleine died here, Judy.
- 我不想去，我宁愿在这里等 - 不行，我需要你
- I don't wanna go. I'd rather wait here. - No, I need you.
为什么？
Why?
我要你当一阵子的麦德琳
I need you to be Madeleine for a while.
等全部结束，我们就都能解脱
And when it's done, we'll both be free.
- 我好害怕 - 不行，我现在要说些麦德琳的事
- I'm scared. - Oh, no. I have to tell you about Madeleine now.
就在那儿
Right there.
我们站在那 那时我最后一次亲吻她
We stood there, and I kissed her for the last time.
她说“如果你失去我
And she said, "If you lose me,
- “要知道我爱你” - 史考特
- "you'll know that I loved you..." - Scottie.
“…而且想要一直爱着你”
"and wanted to keep on loving you."
而我说“我不会失去你” 但我还是失去了
And I said, "I won't lose you." But I did.
她接着转身
And then she turned
跑到教堂里
and ran into the church.
等到我跟着她，已经太迟了
And when I followed her, it was too late.
我不想进去里面！
I don't wanna go in there!
太迟了
It's too late.
史考特，我…
Scottie, I...
我找不到她 然后我在楼梯听到脚步声
I couldn't find her, and then I heard footsteps on the stairs.
她正跑向高塔上层
She was running up the tower.
就在这儿
Right here.
- 史考特… - 瞧？她正跑上楼梯
- Scottie... - See? She was running up the stairs,
穿过暗门到高塔顶端
through the trapdoor at the top of the tower.
而我试着追随她 但我无法上到顶端
And I tried to follow her, but I couldn't get to the top.
我很努力，但无法到顶端去
I tried, but I couldn't get to the top.
一般人通常 没有第二次机会
One doesn't often get a second chance.
我不想被回忆缠身
I want to stop being haunted.
你是我的第二次机会 茱蒂，你是第二次机会
You're my second chance, Judy. You're my second chance.
带我离开！
Take me away!
你现在看起来像麦德琳 上楼梯去
You look like Madeleine now. Go up the stairs.
- 不！ - 走上楼梯
- No! - Go up the stairs.
走上楼梯，茱蒂
Go up the stairs, Judy.
我会跟着
And I'll follow.
我最远只到这儿 但你继续上去
This was as far as I could get, but you went on.
记得吗？
Remember?
项链，麦德琳，你露出破绽了
The necklace, Madeleine. That was the slip.
我还记得项链
I remembered the necklace.
- 让我走！ - 不，我们要上去，麦德琳
- Let me go! - No. We're going up the tower, Madeleine.
你做不到，你会怕！
You can't! You're afraid!
这下，我们走着瞧，走着瞧 这是我的第二次机会
Now, we'll see. We'll see. This is my second chance.
史考特，拜托！
Scottie, please!
但你知道那一天 我无法跟着你上去，对吧？
But you knew that day that I wouldn't be able to follow you, didn't you?
你上去后是谁在那儿？ 艾斯特和他太太？
Who was up there when you got up there? Elster and his wife?
- 是 - 对，死去的是她
- Yes. - Yes, and she was the one who died.
真正的太太，不是你
The real wife, not you.
你只是替身 你是伪装的，对吧？
You were the copy. You were the counterfeit, weren't you?
- 她落下时是生还是… - 死了！死了！他折断她颈子
- Was she dead or alive when... - Dead! Dead! He'd broken her neck.
他折断她颈子 不想冒任何险，是吧？
He'd broken her neck. Wasn't taking any chances, was he?
所以你上来这里后 他把她扔下高塔
So, when you got up there, he pushed her off the tower,
但尖叫的是你 你为何尖叫？
but it was you that screamed. Why did you scream?
我想要阻止，史考特 我跑上去阻止，我…
I wanted to stop it, Scottie. I ran up to stop it. I...
如果你想要阻止 你为何尖叫
If you wanted to stop it, why did you scream,
毕竟你都把我骗得好好的？
since you tricked me so well up to then?
你演的太太非常棒，茱蒂 他把你改头换面的，对吧？
You played the wife very well, Judy. He made you over, didn't he?
他把你改头换面 就像我对你做的，只是他更厉害
He made you over just like I made you over, only better.
不只是衣服和头发
Not only the clothes and the hair,
还有外表，神态跟用字
but the looks, and the manner, and the words,
还有那精湛的恍神
and those beautiful phony trances.
你还跳入海湾，是吧？
And you jumped into the Bay, didn't you?
我猜你一定很会游泳 是不是？是不是？
I'll bet you're a wonderful swimmer, aren't you? Aren't you?
- 是不是？ - 对！
- Aren't you? - Yes!
然后他怎么做？ 训练你？你们有排演吗？
And then what did he do? Did he train you? Did he rehearse you?
他是不是告诉你正确的动作 正确的说词？
Did he tell you exactly what to do, what to say?
你也是个聪明的学徒，是不是？ 你是个很聪明的学徒
You were a very apt pupil, too, weren't you? You were a very apt pupil.
为何挑我？为何是我？
Why did you pick on me? Why me?
你的意外！你的意外
Your accident! Your accident.
我的意外…
My accident...
我是被操弄的人，对吧？
I was the setup, wasn't I?
我是被操弄的人 刻意营造的目击者，我…
I was the setup. I was a made-to-order witness. I...
我做到了
I made it.
- 我做到了 - 你要做什么？
- I made it. - What are you going to do?
我们要上去看看犯罪现场
We're going up and look at the scene of the crime.
来吧，茱蒂
Come on, Judy.
事情在这里发生的
And this is where it happened.
你们两个躲在后面 等着事情平息
And the two of you hid back there and waited for it to clear,
然后你偷溜下来 开回城里，是这样吗？
and then you sneaked down and drove into town, is that it?
然后呢？你是他情人？
And then? You were his girl?
你怎么了？
Well, what happened to you?
你怎么了？他甩了你吗？
What happened to you? Did he ditch you?
茱蒂，他得到所有的遗产 所有的自由，还有权利
Oh, Judy, with all of his wife's money, and all that freedom,
然后甩了你，真是可惜
and that power, and he ditched you. What a shame.
但他知道自己很安全 他知道你不会说，他有给你报酬吗？
But he knew he was safe. He knew you couldn't talk. Did he give you anything?
一些钱
Some money.
还有项链，卡洛塔的项链
And the necklace, Carlotta's necklace.
你就是这时犯错了，茱蒂
And there was where you made your mistake, Judy.
你不该留下凶杀案的纪念品
You shouldn't keep souvenirs of a killing.
你不应该…
You shouldn't have been...
你不应该那么多愁善感
You shouldn't have been that sentimental.
我这么爱你，麦德琳
I loved you so, Madeleine.
史考特
Scottie.
你找到我时，我很安全
I was safe when you found me.
你没有任何的证据
There was nothing that you could prove.
我再次看到你时 实在无法逃离，我太爱你了
When I saw you again, I couldn't run away. I loved you so.
我走入危险 让你改变我，因为我爱你
I walked into danger and let you change me because I loved you,
我想要你
and I wanted you.
史考特，史考特，拜托
Oh, Scottie. Oh, Scottie, please.
你爱我的，现在，保护我吧
You loved me. Now, keep me safe.
- 拜托！ - 太迟了
- Please! - Too late.
太迟了，她再也不会回来了
It's too late. There's no bringing her back.
拜托
Please.
- 不！ - 我听到声音
- No! - I heard voices.
愿上天怜悯她
God have mercy.